<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Coding Intent]]></title>
  <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-22T21:16:24+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://darrencamp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Darren Camp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Thoughts on Xamarin]]></title>
    <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/first-thoughts-on-xamarin/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-02T14:05:39+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/first-thoughts-on-xamarin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the end of my second day of PD on Xamarin. I&rsquo;ve attend a few online classes at Xamarin University and have gone though a couple of labs. My first impressions are that the coding is the same it&rsquo;s just a different UI construction.</p>

<p>For the last 4+ years I&rsquo;ve been in web development so the UI paradigm is a big switch but I imagine that if I had been developing WPF or perhaps WinForms apps then it wouldn&rsquo;t be a big difference at all.</p>

<p>I love the fact I can use C# and .Net to code up an application for the iPhone. I was avoiding iPhone development as I didn&rsquo;t want to learn to use xcode and Objective-C. I have a bunch of languages I want to learn and Objective-C wasn&rsquo;t one of them, so I&rsquo;m grateful that I can use a language I already know.</p>

<p>Thanks Xamarin for a great product and excellent learning resources.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be starting on my sample app over the weekend and continuing it on Monday. I wonder if my opinion will be the same after trying to use it in anger :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today I Start to Look at Xamarin and iOS Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2014/05/01/today-i-start-to-look-at-xamarin-and-ios-development/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-01T12:08:22+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2014/05/01/today-i-start-to-look-at-xamarin-and-ios-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s always difficult to pick something to learn for PD, there&rsquo;s so much out there that I want to explore. This time around I&rsquo;m looking at mobile development with Xamarin, in particular iOS development. I&rsquo;ve been lucky enough to be signed up to Xamarin University. I&rsquo;m planning on getting a certification so I&rsquo;ll be taking a set of online classes to help me achieve that. However I find that I learn best by doing so I need to come up with some sort of simple app that I can develop. A friend and I have been talking about putting together an app to manage the stuff we own and be able to loan our things out to friends and family so I&rsquo;m going with that idea. Here are the user stories I&rsquo;m going to aim for:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>User Story 1:</em>
As the owner of my stuff I want to take a photo of one of my things so that I can loan it out to someone on my contact list.</p></li>
<li><p><em>User Story 2:</em>
As the owner of an item that had been lent out I want to send an sms to the person that is borrowing it so that I can send them a friendly reminder that they have my stuff.</p></li>
<li><p><em>User Story 3:</em>
As the owner of item that has been lent out I want to mark it as returned so that I can use it again or loan it out to another person.</p></li>
<li><p><em>User Story 4:</em>
As the owner of lots of stuff I want to see a list of all my items so that I can see all the items I have and which ones are on loan.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Hopefully by the end of this PD I&rsquo;ll be well on my way to earning that certification and a nice app to start using.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It Lives]]></title>
    <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2014/04/29/it-lives/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-29T12:20:08+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2014/04/29/it-lives</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I followed the bouncing ball and this is where it lead :) Pretty simple to get this blog up and running with github pages and octopress.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WiX on the Build Server]]></title>
    <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2011/05/11/wix-on-the-build-server/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-11T22:20:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2011/05/11/wix-on-the-build-server</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First post in a long while and its about WiX. I was trying to get a WiX project to build without having to install it on the build server. First off I followed this <a href="http://wix.sourceforge.net/manual-wix3/daily_builds.htm">Integrating WiX Projects into Daily Builds</a>. I had to conditionally set the $(SourceCodeControlRoot) like so</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='xml'><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;PropertyGroup&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;SourcesDirectory</span> <span class="na">Condition=</span><span class="s">&quot; $(SourcesDirectory) == &#39;&#39;&quot;</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>$(MSBuildProjectDirectory)\..\<span class="nt">&lt;/SourcesDirectory&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;WixToolPath&gt;</span>$(SourcesDirectory)tools\wix\3.5\<span class="nt">&lt;/WixToolPath&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;WixTargetsPath&gt;</span>$(WixToolPath)Wix.targets<span class="nt">&lt;/WixTargetsPath&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;WixTasksPath&gt;</span>$(WixToolPath)wixtasks.dll<span class="nt">&lt;/WixTasksPath&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;/PropertyGroup&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>However when building the project it crashed visual studio with a help error message like</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;could not load Candle.exe or one of its dependencies, Operation Not Supported&#8221;.</p></blockquote>


<p></p>

<p>Googling turned up a bunch of issues around 64bit image formats which didn&rsquo;t apply. Digging a little deeper revealed this error message</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;An attempt was made to load an assembly from a network location which would have caused the assembly to be sandboxed in previous versions of the .NET Framework. This release of the .NET Framework does not enable CAS policy by default, so this load may be dangerous. If this load is not intended to sandbox the assembly, please enable the loadFromRemoteSources switch. See http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=155569 for more information.&#8221;</p></blockquote>


<p>I wasn&rsquo;t loading it from a network location it was right there on the local file system. I had downloaded the latest binaries zip file for WiX 3.5 and unzipped it straight into the directory like the above link mentions. Since it was download from the interwebs the files had been marked as blocked.</p>

<p>Now what I needed was a way to remove the blocked attribute from all the files, there was no way I wanted to do it manually. Luckily SysInternals has a tool called <a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/bb897440">Streams</a> which will clear that attribute from all files in a directory.</p>

<p>How I got those files into that state in the first place I&rsquo;m not sure because I tried it again and the files weren&rsquo;t blocked. At least I managed to figure it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging Euphoria]]></title>
    <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2008/10/02/debugging-euphoria/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-02T22:23:09+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2008/10/02/debugging-euphoria</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is what coding is all about, searching and searching for that elusive bug and finally terminating it.</p>

<p>Coding is a strange game but one I do love. I hold a senior position at work and consequently I seem to be doing more of the things that don&rsquo;t including coding but this week I was neck deep into debugging. We&rsquo;ve been trying to tack down a performance related bug way down in the comms layer and not having much luck. I was thinking that this coding caper runs you through an emotional rollercoaster. It started with frustration and self doubt about not being able to locate this persistent little creature. Next it was depression and the question of &ldquo;Why am I doing this, I don&rsquo;t need it&rdquo;. After a bit of wallowing in depression the &ldquo;I can do this, it can&rsquo;t be that hard&rdquo; kicks in and you try to pull yourself out of the depression pit. Hope and the light at the end of the tunnel is next and finally, finally the euphoria of success. That euphoria when the bug is finally nailed makes it all worth while and all the bad times seem like a distant memory.</p>

<p>I really do enjoy coding.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
