<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ios | Coding Intent]]></title>
  <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/categories/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-02T15:50:07+09:30</updated>
  <id>http://darrencamp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Darren Camp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today I Start to Look at Xamarin and iOS Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2014/05/01/today-i-start-to-look-at-xamarin-and-ios-development/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-01T13:38:22+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://darrencamp.github.io/blog/2014/05/01/today-i-start-to-look-at-xamarin-and-ios-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s always difficult to pick something to learn for PD, there&rsquo;s so much out there that I want to explore. This time around I&rsquo;m looking at mobile development with Xamarin, in particular iOS development. I&rsquo;ve been lucky enough to be signed up to Xamarin University. I&rsquo;m planning on getting a certification so I&rsquo;ll be taking a set of online classes to help me achieve that. However I find that I learn best by doing so I need to come up with some sort of simple app that I can develop. A friend and I have been talking about putting together an app to manage the stuff we own and be able to loan our things out to friends and family so I&rsquo;m going with that idea. Here are the user stories I&rsquo;m going to aim for:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>User Story 1:</em>
As the owner of my stuff I want to take a photo of one of my things so that I can loan it out to someone on my contact list.</p></li>
<li><p><em>User Story 2:</em>
As the owner of an item that had been lent out I want to send an sms to the person that is borrowing it so that I can send them a friendly reminder that they have my stuff.</p></li>
<li><p><em>User Story 3:</em>
As the owner of item that has been lent out I want to mark it as returned so that I can use it again or loan it out to another person.</p></li>
<li><p><em>User Story 4:</em>
As the owner of lots of stuff I want to see a list of all my items so that I can see all the items I have and which ones are on loan.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Hopefully by the end of this PD I&rsquo;ll be well on my way to earning that certification and a nice app to start using.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
